<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Project Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction between Python and R Studio</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-05-10-python-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-05-10-python-basics/</guid>
      <description>Interaction Between Python and R Studio In this blog, I will demonstrate an example of how Python and R Studio interact. The benefits of integrating multiple languages are that the strengths of both Python and R studio are utilized and therefore more possibilities are available. To begin, I downloaded the reticulate package in order to allow interoperability between Python and R Studio chunks.
All teenagers lie to their parents. They say one thing, but oftentimes, mean something very different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>0. Introduction My dataset for Project 2 is entitled “Automobile” and has 6 variables: fuel-type, body-style, num-of-cylinders, engine-size, city-mpg, and highway-mpg. Three of these variables are categorical and three are numeric. The categorical variables are the fuel type of the car (gas or diesel), body style of the car (convertible, hatchback, etc.), and number of cylinders (four, five, six, etc.). The numeric variables are engine size, city miles per gallon, highway miles per gallon, and price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>0. Introduction The datasets that I have chosen for this project are entitled “SchoolRankings.csv” and “salaries-by-college-type.csv”. The “SchoolRankings”&amp;quot; dataset describes America’s top 150 universities in 2019, pulled from Niche.com. This dataset gives variables such as the name of the school, acceptance rate, location, average cost after financial aid, and the 25th to 75th percentile score on SAT for accepted students. The other dataset, “salaries-by-college-type”, describes the salaries of five different types of schools: Engineering, State, Liberal Arts, Party, and Ivy League.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>